Hello Ajay, Hello friends, I welcome
you to Mash Chilli Powder from Health Insurance.com.
Thank you very much
for watching this video. Happy Diwali to all of you.
Let's start today's topic.
Today's topic is
Health and Health Insurance sector.
Start practicing one thing on the occasion of Diwali. Whenever
Diwali comes in November, December or
October, as your
Diwali crosses, get yourself a health checkup done within 10 or 15 days. There should be at
least four things in the health checkup.
These things are taken care of by the health insurance company
which gives the policy.
Before this, there is your
blood lipid profile in which there are various
parameters, from this side there is
cholesterol, there are many such topics,
along with that, your HBA1C should be included in a health checkup,
but whenever we
check the sugar level of any person, firstly the
random sugar level is checked,
but that is till this type of checkup,
one day we set up that  Today its
median is this much, which was HbA1c, this is a
prevent, your average of the past days comes in it, so
you have taken care of your health for some days, did you not see, you
drank a lot of things on an empty stomach on Diwali, then
after 10-15 days your average will be out, you will like to read this, if
during the period of last 90, what was your blood sugar level,
in any case it should not be above 6,
I will make a separate
video on this, in which you will get the
knowledge about it, thirdly, the
important part in this is the kidney, the
level of the kidney should be checked so that
we can find out at a little early level that no
damage has started inside the kidney,
fourthly, your chapter, these tests for the liver,
these are
considered very important in insurance,
if you want to go over and above, then after
consulting a good doctor once a year,
you should get an ultrasound done, your DJ
system is better, you will find out if there are
any stones etc. inside the kidney, then
you can take care of those things,
Proactively, first you can make some
changes in your lifestyle and you can avail some benefits
and if you still want to take
utmost care of your hands then you should get
a tempered
glass for your hands, which you should get once in 2 years or once
in 5 years.
Normally a good
cardiologist is registered in North Africa,
he will not cost you much,
just subscribe to all the things on this,
then that is the test test,
click on this graph and
subscribe, if you have any
disease then
if we get these five tests done once in a year then
you
can catch one of the diseases that happen inside our body, now if you
want a score, see this
when we are talking about insurance policy, there is a contact there,
free insurance help,
today when you are entering inside the policy, then
try, if you have the option, then take
up that policy, under this your free
insurance medical checkup is being done, those
people who have two-three diseases like BP, sugar,
asthma or two-three other diseases, if you are going through this then
try now without  Do
not take it without health checkup, I am giving
you a disclaimer that today
nine out of ten companies will hang you without
health checkup,
so we must remember our past, we have to take a judgement whether
it is the right step or not to take a policy without medical checkup, if
you want to protect your confidence
or not, if I have to
take it without checkup, then
you should have lost several thousand rupees over the regular period in the last three-four years,
and
you should have maintained the medical legal records, that
when you are entering into a policy,
if health checkup is not done then
what will happen after that, there is
a medical team of the insurance company, they will call you, they
may not call you, then on the basis of whatever statement you have given, the
company will start the policy on the basis of all these
things which are there in the computer when buying a policy,
this is called proposal
form, in the proposal form at least 40-50
diseases are asked, if you have this
disease then  If not, then whenever you are
buying such a policy which
respects you, it is saying just sign here,
I will look into the matter, don't do it,
if you are buying this policy online,
you are not even asked about this thing, do
you have any disease from these 40-50 diseases, that is,
they have listed the
diseases for you, then you should understand that something is going to happen to you,
what is the right way,
I click on any one here, I am
trying to save your money and claim,
you might think that
they wear a lot of short dresses, they watch that channel,
they decide this, there is no
problem, which is called some
guy, so we have to enter this thing carefully, then
like the list of 45 plans from the company, or whatever you are, while
taking which policy,
sit with your family, first of all you should know that
anyone
can come to know at any time, so if you do
not do it, then it seems beautiful to you
that we will give you
four times this, here in
taking a claim of Rs. 10,000  If life is saved then
do not reply too much on those things, do not
trust them completely, do
not believe that there are so many things that
companies are offering, no insurance
company in the whole world likes to give you a claim,
send this thing inside,
understand it as per me, when you make a policy then get your health
checkup done, if you do not take such a pass then
after that you can access your hair options as well,
you can also get the polish,
when you get ₹500 ghee in it, you should get that done,
that too a little bit of your medical record can be
maintained that you got the
checkup done from the listed medical center of the company, now
in the establishment, like in some companies,
health checkup of up to ₹5,000 is
given, now this is over and beyond,
you have put ₹5,000 in a position of ₹3000,
so try to
award such a policy that if you
do this regularly 24  As soon as you have a checkup of ₹5000,
you get it done under your policy
and this year without a policy, then
you get a lot of savings for such a policy.
The amazing thing is that if you do not get it done at all,
then study such a policy a little.
This company helps you by having a
validate feature. This is a facility which is being
liked a lot that when you get the policy
renewed, within the first year itself
you have to make a sacrifice. You should get it done or not.
It depends on you. The insurance company is
not forcing you. The reports are as per the
insurance company cannot do that.
Subscribe to the channel. Those who
try to melt a person,
I will share a small example. There is a
person who contacted us some time back, so
what is it, he alone should do
all the research of his policy. He has also paid
Rs.7000. Now I normally
tell people that you should buy the bank policy, it is
not that it is completed in the end. In the
process of taking the policy, there are
many people in front of you, there are
ghost computers and many others.  They
also do midnight. Now I
told him that if you want to take this policy
from Delhi, but you have to declare all the diseases.
Now he said that the bank which I got this
from the employees of the company is
telling me to put
aside your problem of knee pain. So what was it
because most of the
people do not like what I say, so I
insisted and he said that he is fine, I will
mention it. We talked a little more about the
extra operation, the
surgery which is done on the female,
and there also he was
attached with the scientific company, not the bank, but to him he
told that ma'am
you do not need to tell about this disease, it should be
added in the contract inside the policy. There are
two things here which you have to
link tomorrow, the PAN, which can be
with the replacement or anything, it will be
washed on the old floor.
Why is the person in front refusing you, saying that you should not tell about your pants.
Why is the person in front telling you
that you have this problem of falling, so put it aside.
When you are
investing your money in anything, you are
investing honest money, then you do not understand the logic of hiding it,
then he said to the other person,
your insurance advisor, Zinta or
any call center, tell me a lot of courage in that,
brother, why
remove the responsibility, give your hard earned money yourself,
tell me the things that you know, then
in the last ten-fifteen years, if you have not had this kind of deduction, then how are you care about it,
even if you enter into this policy of childhood between sixty-seventy, you do not have a
doctor for God, who will know whether I have
this disease in my body or not, it could be
any disease,
after getting the borderline introduction, it is cleared, what will you do, then at
that time the dispute happens and there
we go to the companies on social media and
click, these companies are useless,
this is it, all the people who go somewhere and
complain or tell on social media,
I ask a simple question to them, did
you read the proposal form on that policy, did
you read the terms and conditions of this policy, you had
read its thirty-forty page
terms and conditions, that is what
I am equal to now  15 15 pm we study last year
and it took you four days to
read the documents it
is very easy to blame oh what kind of wisdom is this that you are making a
claim to the insurance company it got
negative publicity you have suffered a
loss of 15 lakhs so
don't go on that path so I have one request
understand the importance of health checkup
or not get it done or
it is a very complete subject for the company a person did not
know what is inside it so
subscribe if you ever get a call and the
company can ask any question then you should
bring the answer to it there is a
way to avoid it
you
can do it quickly or else you
subscribe but the company does not report on anything
if the company does its medical
then it is very so
you should take care of this thing my written
message is always Raghbir 90%
so this like and disease diabetes which is subscribed in today's date
all these diseases are
not diseases understand
subscribe a little when you were this year  Then at the
age of 40, there must be some
problem,
diseases, further
diseases do not occur due to some bad air, side effects of sugar are not
diseases, these are very few, how come in this, this
yagya of diseases, by liking and sharing, there is a
disorder, it is very high in this thing,
MB says that how much of your blood
pressure reading, what reading will
we consider correct, when you are stressed, then
your diabetes sugar level increases,
along with eating and drinking, your
space mental, by
writing too much of it with diabetes, hypertension does
not mean blood pressure, blood pressure is a
testing parameter that we have checked the blood pressure,
hypertension or on high means
more and tension means stress, you are
taking a small pill there, which the doctor tells you to take all your
life, but that is
not a cure, the root cause is lying there,
your food pattern which you had since childhood, if you maintain it, you will
not get any disease in life
and if you do not smoke often, then you will not get any disease, when
we were young, we used to sleep at 9:00 at night watching TV,
nowadays  Many times questions are being asked that
we ourselves invite diseases, Uber
screen exposure, fast food all over the world,
in your house the
milk that you buy by paying honest money is adulterated, so the food that you
order online from here is adulterated in it, the
food that is listed in it is junk, job work lunch is also
food, all
other things are included in it, you are going only by
inviting appointments, so
how much purity is there in eating outside food,
drop by drop fills the pot, but bigger than that is
screen time,
exercise has to be done, you are
making alarms for health, no one is getting arrested in any
way, any kind of
government stress, Amit is of the space of the world, he has nurtured the
stress of getting rich quickly, he has become
special about retiring early, all the
tension of the world goes away, you are
sitting comfortably on Facebook, you see someone's
photograph, he has gone for a trip in the second hour,
you start feeling jealous, then this is
knowing that there are scams, Rabbit, so he is
slowly eating your body
from inside by one percent  Mental stress
is the biggest disease and this disease does not come from anywhere,
we ourselves have this thing called animal
husbandry, okay, I do not go to that place of Bigg Boss, it is a
big happy
occasion of Diwali, negative things should be said on it, but
some bitter things happen, if you
want a little then this business
right moment, some other day we will
discuss it a little on like and easy, so
you try this new year which is starting
after Diwali, take
care of your health in this whole year, so whatever you do with the children,
compare it with where you were 10 years ago,
if it has increased many times then
celebrate, there is no need to take much tension, there
is a reverse market in it, this
is a new concept by doing crypto, see
how many people it will speak in the next year,
so you try to stay happy, Hanuman
connects with your culture, whichever religion you
follow, it has a concept in it,
delete a little, you can tweet anywhere,
deleted some in old age home  If we
need something, we can help the poor, we
can donate education to someone, it is a
very good thing, we are also
trying to do the same directly and indirectly, what we want to do
here is that you
join me, if you feel that
you will get some benefit by watching this video, then we
can promote it a little, like it, if you like
something of mine then you
can decide, it will be good for you,
many many happy Diwali to you and your family,
thank you very much for watching this video,
Jai Hind
[Music]